trademark-clearinghouse.com 2015-06-08

# Privacy Notice | www.trademark-clearinghouse.com

## WHO WE ARE

CHIP S.A. (with registered office at: 2, rue Jean Fischbach, 3372 Leudelange, Luxembourg) operates as data controller in charge of the Personal Data processing in relation to the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") and the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") website ([www.trademark-clearinghouse.com](http://www.trademark-clearinghouse.com/)) ( ~~‘~~ our _“_ website ~~’~~ _”_ ), with the support of Deloitte or any Deloitte entity or subcontractor that is providing the Verification Services.") in the capacity of data processors in accordance with appointment of Deloitte or any Deloitte entity or subcontractor that is providing the Verification Services.") by ICANN as Clearinghouse Verification Provider ~~.~~. Deloitte or any Deloitte entity or subcontractor that is providing the Verification Services.") Enterprise Risk Services (a department of Deloitte or any Deloitte entity or subcontractor that is providing the Verification Services.") Bedrijfsrevisoren BV ovve CVBA) (with registered office at: Berkenlaan 8b, 1831 Diegem, Belgium) will serve as the authenticator and validator service provider.

The Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") consists of two primary functions: (i) the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records and (ii) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of NORNs (Notification of Registered Names).

The Clearinghouse Website is designed to provide you with more information in relation to the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program."): the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.

This Privacy Notice is only applicable to the processing of Personal Data by CHIP and Deloitte or any Deloitte entity or subcontractor that is providing the Verification Services.") and covers the processing of Personal Data our website. This Privacy Notice is not a contract between you and CHIP or Deloitte or any Deloitte entity or subcontractor that is providing the Verification Services.") or any other party involved in the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") and is not intended to create any legal rights. The purpose of this Privacy Notice is only to inform you about our processing of your Personal Data.  Capitalized terms used herein have the meanings given to them in the Terms and Conditions for Trademark Agents or Trademark Holders, as applicable.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We will collect and process your Personal Data, including your name, the name of your organization, your contact information, your trademark information, whether you are a Trademark Holder or Trademark Agent, your payment information and any other information necessary to effectuate the purposes of the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.").

We will keep your Personal Data during the time your contract is effective, and as long as required by applicable laws (e.g., due to tax requirements).

If you choose to receive our newsletter, we will also record such preference.

Our website also makes use of cookies. For more information on our use of cookies, please read the section “Our Use of Cookies and similar technologies”.

## YOUR CHOICES

When providing Personal Data on the general contact page, you will be made aware of the mandatory character of the provision of your Personal Data by an asterisk next to the field you have to complete.

We may also ask you if you would like to receive newsletters about our services. We will only send you such newsletter if you have consented to receive them. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletters, please use the opt-out functionality provided in the newsletter or contact us, as explained in the section How To Contact Us.

On your choices on the use of cookies on our website, please see the section “Our Use of Cookies and similar technologies”.

## OUR USE OF COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES

We want to ensure that our website and services are easy to use and reliable. To achieve this, we may use on our website a technology called "cookies", which is a piece of information that our website places on your computer (more specifically your browser) when you access our website.

These pieces of information are used to improve our services for you by, for example:

  * enabling our website to recognize your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task;

  * recognizing that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested; and

  * measuring how many and how people are using our website, so the website can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity.

The cookies used on our website do not store your email address or other directly identifying Personal Data. They do however enable us to recognize your visit, remember your preferences and understand how you interact with our website through the technical information provided by the cookies. We do not use targeting or tracking cookies on our website.

We use the following cookies on our website:

  * Strictly necessary cookies - These cookies are necessary to facilitate basic site functionality. Without these cookies, our website cannot provide the service you request.

This Site uses the following cookies in this category:

Cookie

| 

Technical Cookie Name

| 

Description

| 

Expiration time  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Session Identification cookies

| 

PD-S-SESSION-ID

| 

This cookie will be set on your browser upon access to our website.

It is only used to enable our system to associate the request that you send with the information stored on our system for your session ID.

| 

This cookie is a session cookie which will expire when you close your browser.  
  
User Authentication cookie

| 

PD-ID

| 

This cookie will be set on your browser upon login to our website.

It is only used to offer improved navigation experience to authenticated users in case the back-end server where the user session has been created is unavailable.

| 

This cookie is a session cookie which will expire when you close your browser.  
  
Stickiness cookies

| 

BIGIP-ID

PD_STATEFUL_*

| 

These technical cookies are issued by our systems to ensure your next user requests after your initial request are routed to the same back-end servers where the user session has been created.

| 

These cookies are session cookies which will expire when you close your browser.  
  
Clearinghouse  site cookie settings

| 

cookie_agreed_en

| 

This cookie is used to record that you have accepted the use of cookies on our website.

Without this cookie, you would repeatedly be asked to provide your cookie preferences again.

If this cookie is set, we may set additional cookies (other than strictly necessary cookies), as described below.

| 

This is a permanent cookie which will expire after 3 months after it was set/your last visit.  
  
Performance Cookies - These cookies collect information about how you use our website. This Site uses the following cookies in this category:

Google Analytics

| 

__utma

__utmb

__utmc

__utmz

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. You can read more on Google Analytics at:

| 

2 years from set/update

30 mins from set/update

End of browser session

6 months from set/update  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some website features or services may not function properly without cookies. On most web browsers, you will find a “help” section on the toolbar. Please refer to this section for information on how cookie settings are managed by your web browser. For more information on cookies, please visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

## WHY WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will use your personal data only for the following purposes:

  * Sending newsletters about our services, if you have consented to receive such newsletters;
  * Answer the questions you may ask us about the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") through the contact form;
  * Giving you access to the  Clearinghouse User Interface create and manage your account with us, and \(ii\) submit Trademark Records in order to receive the Verification Services.") and allowing you to submit Trademark Records on the  Clearinghouse User Interface create and manage your account with us, and \(ii\) submit Trademark Records in order to receive the Verification Services.") in order to receive the Verification Services;
  * Perform authentication and validation services, which includes checking if the information provided is accurate and correct and meets the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") Guidelines;
  * Processing financial transactions such as the payment of fees;
  * Comply with the Terms and Conditions of Trademark Agents or Trademark Holders, as applicable;
  * To coordinate with the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (see [www.icann.org](http://www.icann.org/)), registries, registrars and registrants concerning the registration of a domain name that matches a Trademark Record in the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program."); and
  * Offer you customer support.

## WHO RECEIVES YOUR PERSONAL DATA

In order to perform the services we offer, we may have to disclose your Personal Data to the Database Provider, the party appointed by ICANN to operate and manage the central database for storage of Trademark Records that have achieved Activation (i.e. when we have determined that a Trademark Record meets the Eligibility Requirements as stated in the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.") Guidelines).

We may disclose your Personal Data to ICANN, registries, registrars and domain name registrants in order to effectuate the purposes of the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program.").

We may have to disclose your Personal Data in other situations, such as, but not limited to, to comply with legal or regulatory requirements or obligations in accordance with applicable law, a court order, administrative process or judicial process or subpoena.

We will also disclose your Personal Data to a new provider of the Trademark Clearinghouse the authentication of contact information and verification of Trademark Records \(see glossary\) and \(ii\) the storage of such Trademark Records in a database in order to provide information to the new gTLD registries to support the providing of Notification of Registered Name \(NORN\).Whereas Deloitte has been appointed by ICANN to provide the Clearinghouse Verification Services, a part of the Trademark Clearinghouse: the central repository for verified brands for the purpose of protecting brands in ICANN’s new gTLD program."), or our successors and assigns in connection with a merger or sale of our assets.

## TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL DATA TO OTHER COUNTRIES

We will only transfer your Personal Data abroad to the extent necessary to achieve the purposes described in Why We Use Your Personal Data and as described in Who Receives Your Personal Data and will ensure that your transferred Personal Data will enjoy the same level of protection as provided by us.

## YOUR RIGHT OF ACCESS

You have the right to access your Personal Data in order to ensure that your Personal Data is still accurate and up to date.

You have the right to ask us if we hold any Personal Data on you by making an access request. If we hold information about you, we will explain what we have, why we’re holding it and who it could be disclosed to. You may also request to have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

To make such a request, please see the section How to Contact Us..

If we hold Personal Data about you that is incorrect, you may request for us to correct any mistake in the same manner.

## HOW WE SECURE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We recognize the importance of information security, and are constantly reviewing and enhancing our technical, physical, and logical security rules and procedures. We have established technical means, procedures and policies to preserve the integrity, confidentiality and privacy of your Personal Data, during its collection, use, transfer and storage while under our control.

## HOW TO CONTACT US

If you wish to contact us to receive more information on how we process your Personal Data, please send your request to:

  * CHIP S.A.  
2, rue Jean Fischbach  
3372 Leudelange  
Luxembourg

Or send an email to [privacy@trademark-clearinghouse.com](mailto:privacy@trademark-clearinghouse.com).

## CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT

We reserve the right to modify or amend this Privacy Notice at any time and for any reason. For this reason, we urge you to review this statement from time to time while you’re visiting our website. We will however bring explicitly to your attention any operational change that could impact on the choices you have made on our website regarding the processing of your Personal Data.

The Privacy Notice was last updated on 22 March 2013.
